During the mass prayer, while Prophet T.B. Joshua was praying,
he noticed a lady of short stature, praying among the congregation.
How are you?
What are you doing for a living?
I am a student, 300 level.
300 level?
University of where?
AAU (Ambrose Ali University)
You study what?
Computer Science.
The REAL Meaning of FRIENDSHIP – TB Joshua
Watch your screen.
So, you study what?
Computer Science.
I want to be your friend.
Thank you, sir.
Is there any way we can be of help?
The area I need your assistance, if you can assist me, immediately I finish school,
I don’t want to rely on somebody; I want to have something to do.
OK, when you finish the university, you want to have something to do?
So, you don't want to be looking for a job?
OK, don't worry.
We will make sure, we get you established. OK?
Thank you, sir.
People that believe they are tall, they will come to you and ask you for help.
The REAL Meaning of FRIENDSHIP – TB Joshua
Come on.
Where is your friend?
Stepping forward is the friend the lady mentioned to the man of God.
Thank you very much.
Let them sit down.
The two friends sit down together on one chair.
Look for those who need you most.
No matter how small...
Many are out there in need of what you have.
Look for them.
Tell you neighbour: "Look for them".
Moved with compassion, Prophet T.B. Joshua invited the two friends
to come back to The SCOAN the next day,
interested to know more about their plight, and how he can be of assistance to them.
Let's hear what they have to say.
My name is Ehizua Christiana.
I am from Edo State.
I attended Ambrose University, Ekpoma. I studied Political Science Education.
I finished in 2007/2008 and I served 2008/2009.
The person next to me is Evelyn Cosey Otekpe.
She is 27 years old. She is a student of Ambrose Ali University, Ekpoma,
studying Computer Science.
I met her 4 years ago when I was in school.
I saw her and I asked her, “What is happening?”
She said that she did not see anybody that would pick her up; that is why she was crying.
She didn’t have anyone.
Who was crying?
My good friend Evelyn.
She was crying
and when she was shedding tears, I said: “Don’t worry; I will be with you.
I promise to be with you till death does us part”.
And since then, I’ve been with her, doing all things for her -
fetching water for her, buying food, washing clothes.
Whenever it is difficult, she would call me and I would be there for her.
To fetch water from the stream - I would do everything for her.
Even right now, she’s staying with my parents.
She was rejected because many people drive her away; they don't like to see her.
That is why she has nobody to help her.
What actually drew your attention to this sister?
Any time I wash her clothes, I feel joy.
Anywhere I go, we go together.
If she has anything she wants to do, she will call me.
I make her happy.
If we are going out, I will ‘back her’.
Tell us the reason for which you 'back her'.
She finds it difficult to walk long distances.
That is why you 'back her' while you are moving together?
Yes.
Even now, I’m looking for a job – it’s not easy. Because if I had a good job now,
I would have the opportunity to take care of her very well.
She prays for me. Sometimes, if I’m not around or if I forget to pray,
she is the one that will pray for me.
She even helps me to write prayer requests.
Sometimes, she would just ask what my problem was.
I would tell her.
She would say, "Do not worry". She would fast for me, pray for me.
She would say, "God will see you through".
Can you explain to us how you and your friend got to know about the SCOAN?
We watch Emmanuel TV to see what Prophet T.B. Joshua is doing -
encouraging people, playing with them, the less privileged,
the disabled, the handicapped – he’s there for them.
That is why she said, “Christy, we must visit The Synagogue”.
I said, “OK, I will come with you”. That is why we came to Prophet T.B. Joshua.
When we came, it was so difficult for us to enter the church.
We were together on Sunday morning.
The ushers saw her. They said that she should go to the children’s department.
She is 27 years old. She cannot go to the children's department.
She is a student at the university. I was shouting.
It was so difficult.
I’m happy the man of God discovered her because it is not easy.
I’m here because of my friend and I know that God will use the man of God to help us in our need.
Can you tell us your name, your age, and where you come from?
Cosy Evelyn Otekpe. I am 27 years old.
I’m from Edo State, Nigeria.
I attend Ambrose Ali University, Ekpoma, Edo State, Nigeria.
I study Computer Science. I’m now in my final year.
What do you have to say about what your friend has said?
My friend has said everything.
I thank God for giving me such a wonderful friend.
Life was very horrible for me because people reject me.
Before I could get a bike or a bus, I would spend an hour before somebody would come and help me.
But since I met her, she charters buses.
People see me and run away.
Some pick on me and try to mock me, saying:
"Can you see somebody like this?" or: "Where is this one from?"
But since I met her, she has been doing all these jobs -
helping me to get a bike, chartering a bus for me, fetching water for me
helping me to wash clothes - because I cannot trek long distances.
If not because of her, life would have been miserable for me.
Ever since I met her, God has used her in a wonderful way.
At times, she washes my clothes,
she backs me because I cannot walk long distances, she gives me encouragement.
At times, when I think ‘It’s all over’, she makes me realise that there is still hope.
There is not much more to say.
All I have to say is that I give glory to God
for giving me a friend who is so caring like this.
I thank God for everything.
I watch Emmanuel TV in my friend’s house.
I saw the way Pastor T.B. Joshua takes care of the physically challenged -
giving them money and sending them to school.
Because of that, I had the belief that, by the time I see him, God will use him to meet all my needs.
Ever since then, I’ve been forcing my friend to take me to The SCOAN.
During the second service, God did it for me and I was able to see Pastor T.B. Joshua.
But now I’ve seen him, I want God to use him to help me, right from now 'til I finish my school.
I want God to use him to establish me.
I want Pastor T.B. Joshua to help my friend.
I want to tell you today that Jesus values our little effort to honour Him when it is done in humility and faith.
Some people complain that there is no job after your education.
There are jobs; this is God’s job.
When you do this for one or two years, God will provide for you.
Take this challenge and see what God will do for you.
Let them come forward.
This sister needs to be established.
Together the two friends move forward to meet T.B. Joshua.
You know I told you, you are my best friend.
OK?
Well, I want to congratulate you. Thank you very much.
The Lord said to me that He wants to use this sister as a good example to the whole world.
This is God’s job.
The Lord said I should give you a car
and also give you 500 000 Naira.
Thank You, Jesus.
Thank you, Man of God.
No no, it is God.
I'm just a servant.
Give them the key.
The REAL Meaning of FRIENDSHIP – TB Joshua
Watch your screen.
Thank You, Jesus.
There is the key of the car being handed over.
The REAL Meaning of FRIENDSHIP – TB Joshua
The Emmanuel TV team presents the cash gift of 500 000 Naira to the two friends.
Watch your screen - 500 000 Naira, cash.
There is a brand new car
just outside the church auditorium here.
Prophet T.B. Joshua blessed them with a sum of 500 000 Naira and a brand new car.
Hallelujah.
Viewers, we wish to encourage you to do the same.
See your life as a solution to someone in trouble, and look for those who need you the most.
Emmanuel - God is with us.
We are communicating, telling you – do the same.
There are many little people in Africa here.
They are suffering.
They suffer rejection, isolation.
In Africa.
Why can you not walk in public?
Because of the rejection and intimidation.
So, thank you, sister.
I just need to thank you.
OK?
You are a part of our family.
We want to follow it up.
You will come here for holiday, we are one. OK?
Thank you.
Can I give you a kiss please?
Having received a cash gift of 500 000 Naira, a new car, and a promise of a lasting relationship,
the two friends, Miss Evelyn and Christiana, outside of the church auditorium cross the road
to see their beautiful new car.
Taking the key, Mrs Christiana unlocks the door, and helps her friend Evelyn to climb inside,
before she gets into the driver's seat.
Joyfully, the two friends Evelyn and Christiana wave from inside their brand new car.
What a life-changing encounter.
Thank You, Jesus!
Thank you, Man of God - Prophet T.B. Joshua.
I have never dreamt of this. We give God the glory.
Thank You, Jesus.
To God be the glory.
You heard it from the lady, giving thanks to God Almighty for this unexpected gift.
TESTIMONY TIME
My name is Ehizua Christiana. We are from Edo state.
The persons standing beside me are her mother, her elder sister, and our in-law.
Can you just tell the viewers, especially those who were not watching Emmanuel TV,
what actually happened in the church here, the day you were blessed?
We received a car, N500 000 and six bags of rice.
This is the Bible and N500 000.
It was for you and your friend?
Yes.
My name is Cosy Evelyn Otekpe. I am from Edo State.
A student of Ambrose Ali University, Ekpoma, Edo State.
Studying what? And at which year are you?
Computer Science, final year.
The woman standing beside me is my mother.
This is my wonderful elder sister, Christy's in-law and this is my wonderful friend.
Prophet T.B. Joshua blessed us with a gift of a car, N500 000 and also six bags of rice.
These are the particulars of the car.
We thank God Almighty for what He has done in your life.
Let's hear from your mother first.
My name is Agnes Oriwo. I'm 60 years of age.
I came from Edo State because of this little girl, my daughter.
I love her; she’s a clever girl.
Her father sued me to court and we divorced 13 years ago.
What happened was that he said: “I have one child who is not normal.”
Which child is that?
My daughter.
You mean that your husband was referring to your daughter Evelyn?
... that I have one that is not normal.
I wanted to faint but my mother held me and said: "Don't worry, things will be OK."
For the next three days, I didn’t eat anything.
After some time, they organized a church in my room.
Later, she joined the Redeemed Church and became a coordinator of children.
After that, she went outside preaching the Word of God.
I don’t know how to thank the man of God.
She is a burden to me; I don’t know what to say.
She is the one that encourages me and says that whatever a tall person can do, she can also do it.
On Sunday, I saw my daughter on Emmanuel TV and I started crying.
Prophet T.B. Joshua held my daughter and I said: "Ah, my daughter that was rejected!"
He held my daughter and asked her whether she wanted to be his friend.
I started crying. I didn’t know what to say or what to do.
I give God the glory; I thank Prophet T.B. Joshua for my daughter’s life.
I didn’t expect that a man of God could do this.
OK, you can see the mother... Don't worry, mama.
It is a thing of joy.
I don't know what to say.
I give God the glory.
I thank God for what He has done in our life.
Prophet T.B. Joshua gave her N500 000, a car, six bags of rice and a Bible.
I was surprised.
I feel very happy.
That day I did not sleep, it was like I was dreaming.
And now, that the Lord has located you and blessed your daughter
- what word of advice do you have for parents like you
who also have children like this, of this stature and they are underrating what God can do in their life?
They should look up to God; there is no other way.
It’s God’s work. What a man cannot do, God will do it.
Thank you very much.
That is why God used Senior Prophet T.B. Joshua to do this kind of job.
I give God the glory.
Don't cry.
We thank God Almighty for what He has done, and I believe these are just tears of joy you are shedding,
because at the end of the da,y God has blessed your daughter abundantly.
Yes.
I am Christy Kiaham from Abuja.
This is my mummy, my younger sister. I’m the second born of my mummy.
My mummy has been the one taking care of us.
The REAL Meaning of FRIENDSHIP – TB Joshua
When I am at home, I do assist her, we go to the village market
to sell ice-cream to assist her for my brothers' and sisters' school fees.
During the mass prayer, my prayer point was: ‘God, locate Evelyn.’
Behold – after few seconds, the man of God located her.
I was rejoicing because I believed that all the problems we were facing had been solved.
To my greatest surprise, the man of God called her and said: "I want to be your friend",
I was crying. It was a thing of joy.
I didn’t expect this. Among thousands for the man of God to locate somebody like this
- it was a great joy.
I thank God for the life of Prophet T.B. Joshua.
May God bless him and his family and the Emmanuel TV team.
She was given with her friend a brand new car, N500 000, six bags of rice and a Bible.
My heart was full of joy.
God, I thank You for using the man of God to locate my sister, to bless my sister.
God, I give You all the glory, honour, I adore You.
There is no one like You.
Despite her stature, the man of God received her as his daughter.
I want to advise people all over the world, don’t lose hope.
No matter your stature – believe in God.
Pray.
As God located my sister, He will surely locate you.
Amen.
My name is Okweki Lucky. I’m from Edo State.
I married the immediate senior sister to Christy here.
Four years ago, Christy brought this girl to our house, and introduced her to be her friend.
Instead of rejecting her, we accepted her to our family,
and ever since, she has been a source of joy to our family.
Last Sunday I was watching Emmanuel TV.
I was so surprised to see the man of God calling this girl out.
Later I saw that the man of God presented a gift of N500 000 to them,
a brand new car and six bags of rice.
We were rejoicing over there in Edo State.
That is why we came to rejoice with them.
Yes, we thank God Almighty for everything.
We also thank you so much for taking time out of your tight schedule to come here
to show appreciation to God Almighty, for what God has used the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua,
to do in the life of your sister-in-law, and your sister-in-law's friend,
and of course your sister-in-law's friend family.
We also want to let you know that of course, it is the work of God,
and God does as He wills and of course, God's time is the best.
The moment God Almighty locates you, even in your trouble, your trouble will turn to solution.
That happened in the life of our two friends here.
We also believe that God will extend it to lives of others.
We want to encourage our friends here to continue their relationship,
which has been founded upon the Rock of Ages.
This kind of friendship is a type of friendship that Jesus Christ is looking for to bless them,
to cement the relationship the more.
We pray that the joy of the Lord that has actually commenced in this family
will continue to reign, in Jesus' name.
Can we just hear a wonderful song from someone after this really wonderful testimony?
The REAL Meaning of FRIENDSHIP – TB Joshua
Praise the Lord!
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe, to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today
and stay up-to-date with the latest prophecies, deliverances,
sermons and testimonies from the Synagogue Church Of All Nations.
Emmanuel TV – Changing lives, Changing nations and Changing the world.
TT Robert Begier 15/06/2018
RV Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 22/06/2018 + Mel